Contact

kittsutton@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kittysutton-900703b (LinkedIn) www.aka1908.com/past (Other)

Top Skills

Patient Safety
Hospitals
Healthcare

Languages

English

Certifications

Certified Nurse Operating Room (CNOR)

Kitty Sutton

Operating Room Nurse at CHI St. Luke's Health Houston. Texas Area

Summary

Quality Management/Project Coordinator/OR Circulator. Skilled and dedicated Registered Nurse with a 20+ year track record of providing quality, patient-centered care in the acute care setting. Diversely experienced with a comprehensive background in nursing care and healthcare administration.

Experience

CHI St. Luke's Health - Baylor St. Luke's Medical Center 19 years

Operating Room Nurse, RN, MSN, CNOR February 2016 - Present (4 years 4 months) Sugar Land, Texas

Evaluates operating room patients and plans, implements and documents nursing care. Assists physicians during surgical procedures. Functions in a scrub and circulating nurse role. Provide nurse/scrub tech education, clinical supervision and evaluation of personnel.

Medical Staff Quality Coordinator, RN, MSN, CNOR 2009 - Present (11 years)

Interprets, explains and follows all regulatory guidelines, including medical staff bylaws, fair hearing plan, rules and regulations and polices. Maintains systems to identify (and disseminate to others) medical staff members and their clinical privileges, prepares and maintains other related records and reports.

Works with medical staff leadership and hospital clinical staff for the approval and ongoing review of these practitioners. Monitors and revises credentialing and privileging forms as needed. Ensures maintenance of medical staff and allied health staff files.

Ensures that results of medical staff quality management findings are provided to appropriate review committees/ departments and maintained in a confidential file. Coordinates continuing medical education programs

for the medical staff and ensures compliance with the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organization (JCAHO) and other regulatory organizations.

Orthopedic Nurse Coordinator, RN, BSN, CNOR 2001 - 2009 (8 years)

Employed critical thinking to integrate objective data with knowledge gained from an assessment of the subjective experiences of patients.

Utilized the critical thinking process to apply the best available evidence and research data to the processes of diagnosis and treatment.

Evaluated quality and effectiveness of nursing practice to optimize patient outcomes. Applied medical/clinical knowledge, technical and clinical skills, clinical judgment, interpersonal skills and communication as indicated in the current Comprehensive Accreditation Manual for Hospitals.

Education

Capella University

Master's Degree, Nursing Science · (2013 - 2015)

Texas Woman's University
Bachelor's Degree, Nursing · (2002 - 2006)

Wharton College
Associate's Degree, Nursing Science · (1993 - 1995)

Texas Southern University
Bachelor's Degree, Finance · (1983 - 1987)